最专业冰火字幕
诚意奉献
专注GOT剧集
翻译 喵羽
翻译 SaintHS
翻译 依依eva
君临 King's Landing
红堡
Red Keep
翻译 埃尔夫歪
校对 屈畅   赵琳
派
Pyke
克
城
校对 运气哥
后期 SerGawen@huiji.wiki
临冬城
Winterfell
监制 北落师门
监制 临冬城的狮子
最专业的华语冰火资料站：        冰与火之歌中文维基
http://asoiaf.huiji.wiki
技术支持 灰机T.R.A.N.S.
绝境长城 the Wall
策划 衣柜军团
联合出品
史诗图书 | 冰火中文维基 | 黑城堡奇幻微刊
Epic Books         SOIAF.huiji.wiki          Heichengbao
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
特别顾问 屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
维斯·多斯拉克
Vaes Dothrak
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
衣柜字幕组
协力制作
史诗图书
Epic Books
ASOIAF.huiji.wiki
冰火中文维基
黑城堡
EPICASTLE
第三集
破誓者
Oathbreaker
戴佛斯·席渥斯
洋葱骑士
琼恩·雪诺
慢点 慢点
Easy, easy.
慢点
Easy.
梅丽珊卓
你都记得什么？
What do you remember?
他们捅了我
They stabbed me.
奥利……
Olly...
他一刀扎进我的心脏
he put a knife in my heart.
我应该死了
I shouldn't be here.
红袍女士令你死而复生
The lady brought you back.
后来呢 他们捅了你之后
Afterwards, after they stabbed you,
你死之后 去了什么地方？
after you died, where did you go?
看到了什么？
What did you see?
没有
Nothing.
什么都没有
There was nothing at all.
真主带你回来必有原因
The Lord let you come back for a reason.
史坦尼斯并非预言中的王子
Stannis was not the prince who was promised,
但总有人是
but someone has to be.
能让我俩单独待会儿么？
Could you give us a moment?
你死了
You were dead.
现在又活了
And now you're not.
要我看 这件事疯狂到了极点
That's completely fucking mad, seems to me.
我没法想象你自己怎么看
I can only imagine how it seems to you.
我做了自认为正确的事
I did what I thought was right.
结果被人谋害
And I got murdered for it.
现在我又复活了
And now I'm back.
为什么？
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
或许我们永远不会知道
Maybe we'll never know.
但这重要吗？
What does it matter?
你继续前行
You go on.
只要一息尚存 就去战斗
You fight for as long as you can.
尽可能摆平这些破事
You clean up as much of the shit as you can.
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know how to do that.
我以为自己知道 可……
I thought I did, but...
可我失败了
I failed.
很好
Good.
不妨多失败几次
Now go fail again.
忧郁的艾迪
托蒙德
野人头领
他们以为你是神
They think you're some kind of god.
所以才会死而复生
The man who returned from the dead.
我不是神
I'm not a god.
我知道
I know that.
我看了你的鸡鸡
I saw your pecker.
神的鸡鸡哪能那么小？
What kind of god would have a pecker that small?
你的眼睛还是棕色
Your eyes are still brown.
但你还是你吗？
Is that still you in there?
应该还是
I think so.
你得等等才能烧掉我了
Hold off on burning my body for now.
真好笑
That's funny.
你确定你还是你？
You sure that's still you in there?
吉莉
山姆威尔·塔利
你还好吗？
You all right?
好 好 我没事
Yes. Yes, I'm fine.
我有没有告诉过你 我曾以为大洋念做“扬”
Did I ever tell you I used to think the sea was called the see
因为一眼望去全是水波扬起？
because it was nothing but water as far as the eye could see?
没有吧
I don't think so.
洋 扬
Sea, see.
它们写法不同 发音却一样
They're spelled different, but they sound the same.
对 是啊
Yeah, they do.
当然 这是在我识字之前的事了
It was before I learned how to read, obviously.
山姆 你是不是病了？
Sam, are you going to be sick?
坚持一下 很快就到南方了
Won't be long. We'll be in the south soon.
想想能看到旧镇我就激动
I'm excited to see Oldtown.
船长说旧镇是维斯特洛最美的城市
Captain says it's the most beautiful city in Westeros.
你又想吐？
Are you going to vomit again?
不不不 只是……
No. No, no, no. I'm...
学城不准女人进
The Citadel doesn't admit women.
你和小山姆不能住在那儿
There won't be a place for you there or for Little Sam.
黑城堡也不准女人进 我不也住了很久？
I stayed at Castle Black. There's no women allowed there.
学城跟黑城堡不一样
The Citadel isn't Castle Black.
那儿没有琼恩·雪诺或伊蒙学士帮我行方便
I don't have a Jon Snow or Maester Aemon to help me bend the rules.
那我住旧镇好了
I'll stay in Oldtown, then.
你一个人？
By yourself?
带个孩子 身无分文？
With a baby and no money?
不去旧镇的话
So if we're not going to Oldtown,
你要带我去哪儿？
where are you taking me?
去我家
To my home.
角陵
Horn Hill.
我爹……算了 别指望他了
My father's... well, my father,
不过我妈心肠很好 我妹妹人也不错
but my mother's a kind woman and my sister's lovely.
她们会照顾你们母子
They'll take care of you both.
“不管你去哪儿 我都跟你一起”
"Wherever you go, I go, too."
这可是你说的
That's what you said.
我这么说 是因为我希望你和小山姆平安
I said that because I want you and Little Sam to be safe.
这是我唯一的心愿
That's all I want...
如果我能当上学士 到时候就能辅助琼恩
to become a maester so I can help Jon when the time comes
你们也就安全了
so you'll be safe.
你要帮我们 还要帮世界上其他的……
Us and everyone else in the world.
我才不在乎其他人
I don't care about them.
好吧 我在乎 但不是特别在乎
Well, no, I do, but I don't really.
我在乎的是你和他
I care about you and him.
我知道 山姆
I know that, Sam.
他也知道
And he does, too.
只有你真正在乎我们
You're the only one who ever has.
如果你觉得这么做最好
If you think it's for the best,
我们就听你的
we trust you.
我宁可你用东西砸我 然后跑掉
I'd feel better if you threw something at me and stormed off.
我绝不会对我孩子的爹那么做
I'd never do that to the father of my son.
布兰
三眼乌鸦
那是我父亲
That's my father.
他旁边是霍兰·黎德
The man beside him is Howland Reed,
梅拉的父亲
Meera's father.
亚瑟·戴恩爵士
Ser Arthur Dayne.
拂晓神剑
The Sword of the Morning.
父亲说亚瑟·戴恩是他见过最强的剑士
Father said he was the best swordsman he ever saw.
史塔克大人
Lord Stark.
我在三叉戟河上没见到你们
I looked for you on the Trident.
我们不在那里
We weren't there.
我们在的话
Your friend the usurper
你的篡夺者朋友就该入土了
would lie beneath the ground if we had been.
疯王已死
The Mad King is dead.
入土的则是雷加
Rhaegar lies beneath the ground.
你们为何不去守护你们的王子？
Why weren't you there to protect your prince?
王子命我们在此守护
Our prince wanted us here.
我妹妹呢？
Where's my sister?
在未来的战争中 祝你们好运
I wish you good fortune in the wars to come.
一切就从这里开始吧
And now it begins.
不对
No.
一切将在这里结束
Now it ends.
他比我父亲强
He's better than my father.
强得多
Far better.
但我父亲打败了他
But Father beat him.
真的？
Did he?
我知道是真的
I know he did.
这故事我都听一千遍了
Heard the story a thousand times.
他在背后捅刀
He stabbed him in the back.
谁在塔里？
What's in the tower?
今天看得差不多了
That's enough for one day.
改天继续
We'll visit again another time.
- 我只想看看他去了哪里
- 该走了
- I want to see where he's going. - Time to go.
父亲！
Father!
你为何这么做？
Why did you do that?
带我回去那里 我要回去
Take me back there. I want to go back.
不行
No.
- 他听到我叫他了
- 也许吧
- He heard me. - Maybe.
- 也许他只是听到了风声
- 他听到我了
- Maybe he heard the wind. - He heard me.
过去已成过去 一切都已盖棺定论
The past is already written. The ink is dry.
谁在塔里？
What's in that tower?
我要回去看看
I want to go back there.
我告诉过你无数次
I've told you many times, stay too long
在不属于你的时空停留过久 就回不来了
where you don't belong and you will never return.
我干嘛回来？
Why do I want to return?
就为继续当个残废？
So I can be a cripple again?
跟长在树里的老家伙闲扯淡？
So I can talk to an old man in a tree?
你以为我愿意在这里坐上一千年
You think I wanted to sit here for 1,000 years
极目远眺这个世界
watching the world from a distance
任由树根长进我的身体？
as the roots grew through me?
那你到底为什么？
So why did you?
因为我在等你
I was waiting for you.
我可不想变成你这样
I don't want to be you.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
你不会永远待在这儿
You won't be here forever.
你不会变成树里的老家伙
You won't be an old man in a tree.
但离开之前
But before you leave,
你必须学习
you must learn.
学什么？
Learn what?
一切
Everything.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
嘿 伟大的卡丽熙 动动你的屁股
欢迎回家 卡丽熙
退下
你们干嘛？！
把你们的手拿开！
我要砍你们的头！
你犯了个大错
你会后悔的
我是伟大卡奥的妻子
我们知道你是谁
我还记得你当众吃下马心
卓戈卡奥死后 你为什么不回来？
因为我是风暴降生丹妮莉丝
解放者
弥林女王 龙之母
我不会在这里陪你们终老
你是伟大卡奥的妻子
你以为自己会陪在他身边 陪他征服世界
他却死了
_
我也曾是伟大卡奥的妻子
萨沃卡奥
_
我也以为自己会陪在他身边 陪他征服世界
你还太年轻
我们都年轻过
但我们都接受了现实
你也学着接受吧
如果你足够幸运 能与我们终老的话
我还能去哪儿呢？
每个卡丽熙最终都会成为多希卡林
对 在她们的卡奥死后立刻成为
你却继续在外游荡
这可犯了大忌
所有卡拉萨都会来参加卡拉萨大会
一起决定洗劫哪些城市 奴役哪些部落
现在他们必须决定如何处置卓戈卡奥的银发遗孀
幸运的话 你会留下陪我们终老 龙之母
这是你最好的结局
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛”
真搞不懂 你们居然还穿得住一身皮甲
I don't know how you stand it in all that leather.
能让我们单独谈谈吗
If we could have the room.
你今天好美 亲爱的 真的
You look lovely today, my dear. You really do.
你怎么做到汗都不流就爬完这些台阶的？
How you climbed all those steps without breaking a sweat.
你要是想拷问我
If you're going to torture me,
叫他们回来动手就行
just call them back and get on with it.
我可不是拷问者
I am not a torturer.
尽管很多时候有些人活该受虐
Though it so often is what people deserve.
拷打的确也能问出答案
And it does provide answers.
不过通常都是错误答案罢了
But they're usually the wrong answers.
我的任务却是找到正确答案
My job is to find the right answers.
知道我会怎么做吗？
Do you know how I do that?
我会让人开心
I do it by making people happy.
我也想让你开心 瓦拉
I'd like to make you happy, Vala.
这是你的名字 对吧 瓦拉？
That's your name, isn't it, Vala?
不说也没关系
That's all right.
我知道你是谁 知道你做过什么
I know who you are and what you've done.
你还真做了不少呢
You've done a lot.
你为达目的献出了你的身体
You've sacrificed your body for a cause,
这就已经比大部分人做得多了
which is more than most people do.
你还帮助鹰身女妖之子
And you've helped the Sons of the Harpy
谋杀无垢者和次子团的人
murder the Unsullied and the Second Sons.
无垢者和次子团是外国的战士
The Unsullied and the Second Sons are foreign soldiers
由外国的女王带领
brought here by a foreign queen
毁掉了我们的城市与历史
to destroy our city and our history.
我明白了
I understand.
从你的立场看
Well, that makes perfect sense
你的行为无可指责
from your perspective.
当然了 你我立场不同
I have a different perspective, of course.
我觉得 重点是你应该站在我的立场上想想问题
I think it's important that you try to see things from my perspective
正如我也会试着换位思考
just as I will try to see them from yours.
因为这是我让你和多姆都开心
Because that is the only way
的唯一办法
that I can make you and Dom happy.
是这么发音吧 多姆？
That is how you pronounce it... Dom?
很抱歉我不太擅长这种语言
I'm afraid I don't really speak the language.
多么帅气的男孩
Such a handsome boy.
那双棕色的大眼睛 希望不要太招女生喜欢
Those big, brown eyes. Good luck keeping the ladies away.
呵 你还真是个解放者 对吗？
Yes, you're a true liberator, aren't you?
你不会拷问我 只会用我儿子作要挟
You won't torture me, you'll just threaten my son.
孩子是无辜的
Children are blameless.
我从没伤害过他们
I have never hurt them.
你儿子目前没危险
Your boy is in no immediate danger,
我向你发誓
this I swear to you.
至于你呢 亲爱的
But between us, dear,
你曾密谋杀害女王的士兵
you did conspire to kill the queen's soldiers.
我们都明白你将面临何种刑罚
We both know the penalty for that crime.
没了母亲 可怜的多姆该怎么活？
How will poor Dom get on without his mother?
他还有气喘病
And with his breathing problem.
哪怕我招了一个字 他们都会杀了我
If I tell you anything, they'll kill me.
就算你不杀我 他们也会
So either you kill me or they do.
是啊 站在你的立场 这是个问题
Yes, from your perspective, this is a problem.
但你还有第三个选择
There is a third option, though.
明天有艘船去潘托斯
A ship leaving tomorrow for Pentos.
我已经帮一个女人和她儿子订了位置
I've already booked passage for a woman and her young son.
还留下一袋银币帮你们重新开始
I'll even throw in a bag of silver to help you start again.
不过 恐怕我得
Though I'm afraid we'll have to ask
喊一个穿皮甲的朋友帮你扛出去
one of our leather-clad friends back in to carry it.
我觉得袋子太沉了
Far too heavy for me.
明天天一亮就开船
The boat sails at dawn.
你必须马上做决定
You need to decide now.
是你和多姆开始新的生活
A new life for you and Dom
还是……
or...
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔”
灰虫子
弥桑黛
就这么干等？
What should we do while we wait?
不如干点什么打发时间吧？
To pass the time, what should we do?
不聊点什么？
What should we talk about?
你会说十九种语言
You speak 19 languages.
偶尔用它们聊聊天总可以吧
You must occasionally use some of them to talk about things.
你们俩 总是待在一起
You two, you spend a great deal of time together.
我不在的话 你们会聊什么？
What would you be talking about if I weren't here?
巡逻
Patrol.
聊我带领无垢者一起巡逻的事
When I am going on patrol with the Unsullied.
我们巡逻时看到了什么
What we see on patrol.
巡逻时抓住了谁
Who we captured on patrol.
很好 非常好
That's good. That's very good.
但这只是报告
But that's a report.
我觉得聊天不止如此
I was thinking more of a conversation.
有位智者说过 真正的世界历史
A wise man once said the true history of the world
由豪华房间里发生的伟大聊天组成
is the history of great conversations in elegant rooms.
谁说的？
Who said this?
我
Me.
刚说完
Just now.
好吧 不聊天
All right, no conversations.
那就玩个游戏
Let's play a game.
你俩不玩游戏吗 从没玩过？
You don't play games, either one of you, ever?
游戏是小孩玩的
Games are for children.
我曾经的主人克拉兹尼有时会让我们玩游戏
My master Kraznys would sometimes make us play games.
看 一个好的开始
There, that's a start.
- 但只有女孩能玩 - 不不不
- Only the girls. - No, no, no.
不是 当然不是那种游戏
Not that. Of course not that.
我是说 纯洁又好玩的游戏
Innocent games. Fun games.
喝酒游戏
Drinking games.
我们不喝酒
We do not drink.
直到你们破戒
Until you do.
好吧 不喝酒
All right. No drinking.
不喝也能玩
We can play without drinking.
这是个很棒的游戏 我发明的
It's a wonderful game. I invented it.
规则如下
Here's how it works.
我猜你们的过去
I make a statement about your past.
如果我猜错了 罚酒
If I'm wrong, I drink.
如果我猜对了……
And if I'm right...
不喝酒可能就玩不下去了
maybe we can't play without drinking.
哦 你真够准时的
Oh, you took your time.
不好意思
Sorry.
我忙着打听究竟是谁资助鹰身女妖之子
I was busy learning who funds the Sons of the Harpy.
- 有些事情你急不得 - 你找到了吗？
- Some things you can't rush. - You found out?
阿斯塔波的善主
The Good Masters of Astapor
还有渊凯的贤主
and the Wise Masters of Yunkai.
以及他们的瓦兰提斯朋友
With help from their friends in Volantis.
你看？
You see?
你根本不用担心本地的叛乱
You don't even have to worry about the local rebellion.
我们只需要担心
We only have to worry about
三个资助他们的富有城邦
the three rich foreign cities paying for it.
我们曾经征服过阿斯塔波和渊凯
We conquered Astapor and Yunkai once.
我们可再次征服他们 并处决那些奴隶主
We will do it again and execute the Masters.
若无垢者出兵重夺阿斯塔波和渊凯
If the Unsullied march off to reconquer Astapor and Yunkai,
谁留下保卫弥林的自由民？
who will remain to defend the free people of Meereen?
如果不出兵 如何阻止流血
If we do not fight them, how can we stop them?
我们阻止不了
We cannot.
奴隶主只说一种语言
The Masters speak only one language.
多年来他们一直对我说这种语言
They spoke it to me for many years.
我了解它更胜母语
I know it better than my mother tongue.
想让他们听话 我们必须用这种语言回敬
If we want them to hear us, we must speak it back to them.
让这些话为他们送终
May it be the last thing they ever hear.
也许只能如此
You may be right.
所以要打了？
So we will fight them?
- 可能 - 可能？
- Possibly. - Possibly?
这就是聊天
It's a conversation.
告诉我 你的小小鸟儿能把消息传到
Tell me, can your little birds get a message
阿斯塔波的善主 渊凯的贤主
to the Good Masters of Astapor, the Wise Masters of Yunkai,
以及瓦兰提斯仁慈的奴隶贩子那里去么？
and benevolent enslavers of Volantis?
当然 人无常善变
Of course. Men can be fickle,
但小小鸟们永远值得信任
but birds I always trust.
exclusive from -tusubt-itulo=-.co/m
亚瑟 你的眼睛看起来好多了
Your eye looks much better, Arthur.
科本
你母亲的下巴怎么样了？
How's your mother's jaw?
好点了
Better.
你父亲呢？
And your father?
再没人见过他
No one's seen him.
也不会有人再见到他
And no one will.
这结果相当不错
That worked out rather nicely.
瓦里斯大人会回来吗？
Will Lord Varys ever come back?
我觉得他不会了
I don't think so.
你很想他吗？
Do you miss him?
他人很好
He was nice.
他管我们叫小小鸟儿
He called us his little birds.
他给我们糖吃
He gave us sweets.
说起这个可就有意思了
It's funny you should mention that.
猜猜我今天碰巧找到了什么
Guess what I happened to find today.
多恩的梅子蜜饯
Candied plums from Dorne.
记住 如果你们的伙伴
Now remember, if any of your friends
喜欢吃糖果 或者需要帮助 尽管来找我
like sweets or need help, they can always come to me.
只需跟我说说悄悄话
All I need in return are whispers.
不用害怕
No need to be afraid.
这位是格雷果爵士
This is Ser Gregor.
我的朋友就是他的朋友
He's friends with all my friends.
劳勃·斯壮
御林铁卫
快走吧
Run along now.
詹姆·兰尼斯特
瑟曦
瓦里斯的小小鸟吗？
Varys's little birds?
现在是您的小小鸟 陛下
Your little birds now, Your Grace.
你到底对他做了什么？
What did you do to him exactly?
我一直没能弄清楚
I haven't been able to get a clear answer.
哦 我做了很多事情
Oh, a number of things.
他能明白我们在说什么吗？
Does he understand what we're saying?
我是说 可以像以前那样
I mean, to the extent that he ever understood
理解完整句子吗？
complete sentences in the first place.
完全可以
He understands well enough.
那就告诉他杀去圣堂
So tell him to march into the sept
把大麻雀的脑袋瓜捏碎
and crush the High Sparrow's head like a melon.
大麻雀有数百人的教团武装保护他
The High Sparrow has hundreds of Faith Militant surrounding him.
格雷果爵士没办法对付他们所有人
Ser Gregor can't face them all.
他也不需要
And he won't have to.
他只需要对付一个
He'll only have to face one.
教会提出正式的指控了吗？
Has the Faith leveled official charges yet?
还没有
Not yet.
我真期待见证这场比武审判
That is one trial by combat I look forward to watching.
别局限于君临
Don't stop at the city.
我要小小鸟去多恩
I want little birds in Dorne,
去高庭 去北境
in Highgarden, in the North.
如果有人想看我们的笑话 坐收渔利
If someone is planning on making our losses their gains,
我要知道
I want to hear it.
如果有人敢嘲笑他们的太后
If someone is laughing at the queen
说她赤身游街 满身污垢
who walked naked through the streets covered in shit,
我要知道
I want to hear.
我要知道他们是谁
I want to know who they are.
他们人在何处
I want to know where they are.
- 和瓦里斯大人一样坏 - 科本还要更坏
- As bad as Lord Varys was, - Qyburn is worse.
我跟他们都说了 我说了
I told them all. I told them.
派席尔
学士
他傲慢 危险
He's arrogant, dangerous.
他不会无缘无故地就被赶出学城
You don't get thrown out of the Citadel without good reason.
奥莲娜·雷德温
荆棘女王
但没有人听我的话
And no one listened to my advice.
所以才成了今天这样
So here we are.
他在格雷果·克里冈身上做的事是邪恶的
And what he's done to Gregor Clegane is an abomination.
我们从未同意这个实验
We never sanctioned this experiment.
我个人认为我们最好
I for one think it will be in our best interest
把这个野兽杀……
to have the beast dest...
梅斯·提利尔
凯冯·兰尼斯特
国王之手
- 有什么可以效劳的吗？ - 你怎么在这？
- Can I help you? - Why are you here?
- 我的母亲…… - 亲爱的 我被邀请来
- My mother... - I was invited, my dear,
帮助解决一些棘手的问题
to help deal with several troublesome issues,
譬如王后被监禁
such as the queen's imprisonment.
亏你还提起这个
Thank you for bringing it up.
我们早就该讨论如何应对我所受的侮辱了
It's well past time we addressed the abuses I endured.
玛格丽才是王后
Margaery is the queen.
你不是
You are not the queen
因为你没有嫁给国王
because you're not married to the king.
我能明白你们家族里
I do appreciate these things
这些事情搞得有点混乱
can get a bit confusing in your family.
这里是御前会议
This is a small council meeting.
你无权出席御前会议
You have no position on the small council.
我是御林铁卫队长
I'm the Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
御林铁卫队长
The Lord Commander of the Kingsguard
有权出席御前会议
does have a position on the small council.
派席尔大学士 你认可吗？
Grand Maester Pycelle, would you sanction that statement?
呃……
Well...
杰洛·海塔尔爵士
I would say Ser Gerold Hightower
曾在疯王的御前会议有一席之地
had a seat on the Mad King's council.
但当然了 那是疯王
Of course, that was the Mad King.
劳勃国王认为不可
King Robert saw things differently.
而乔……
And King...
弥赛菈的死怎么说 叔叔？
What about Myrcella's death, Uncle?
您认为血亲被谋杀
Do you consider the murder of your own blood
是一个棘手的问题么？
a troublesome issue?
谋杀弥赛菈的那个女人
The same women who murdered Myrcella
推翻了马泰尔家族 控制了多恩
have overthrown House Martell and taken control of Dorne.
我们需要讨论的问题太多了
We've got a lot to discuss.
我们所有人 一起
All of us together.
既然你们无法让我们离开 就继续吧
And seeing as you cannot make us leave, we best get on with it.
的确 我们无法让你们离开
No, we cannot make you leave.
而你们也无法强迫我们留在这
And you cannot make us stay.
除非你让那东西把我们都杀了
Not unless you're gonna have that thing murder us all.
大麻雀
总主教
陛下
Your Grace.
我母亲想来看望她女儿最后的安息之地
My mother would like to see her daughter's final resting place.
抱歉 陛下
I'm sorry, Your Grace.
这不可以 现在还不行
That's not possible. Not yet.
那何时可以？
When will it be possible?
拖曼·拜拉席恩一世
直到她赎清罪孽
When she's fully atoned for her sins.
你已斩下她的头发
You cut off her hair and marched her naked
令她在众目睽睽之下赤裸游行
through the streets in front of the whole city.
这还不够赎罪吗？
That wasn't the full atonement?!
不
No.
她必须在七位修士面前接受审判
She must stand trial before seven septons
让我们了解她的全部罪行
so we can learn the true extent of her sins.
我要你打开大门 让她来看望弥赛菈的安息之地
I want you to let her see Myrcella's resting place.
我是国王
I am the king.
没错
You are.
那么这对你意味着什么？
And what does that mean to you?
这对我意义非凡
It means a great deal to me.
王权与信仰
The Crown and the Faith
乃是世界的两大支柱
are the twin pillars of the world.
您知道这话是谁告诉我的？
Do you know who told me that?
您母亲
Your mother.
我那个“不洁”的母亲？
My mother who is unclean?
我那个经受你种种折磨 却仍需赎罪的母亲？
My mother who still needs to atone after all you've put her through?
您认为圣母首度降临是何情形？
How do you think the Mother Above first came to us?
世上的男男女女
How did men and women
如何首度感受到圣母的存在？
first come to feel the Mother's presence?
是通过自己的母亲
It was through their own mothers.
瑟曦非常虚伪 这点您心知肚明
There's a great deal of falsehood in Cersei. You know that.
但当她谈及您时 母爱胜过了一切
But when she speaks of you, the Mother's love outshines it all.
她对您的爱
Her love for you is more real
比世上任何东西都要真实
than anything else in this world
因为这种爱并非来自这个世界
because it doesn't come from this world.
这点其实您也知道
But you know that.
您亲身感受过
You've felt it.
她对您说话的时候 您看见了圣母的影子
You've seen her when she talks to you.
是的
Yes.
这是一件无与伦比的礼物
It's a great gift.
我从未得到过
One I never had.
嫉妒
Envy.
又一项我应当忏悔的罪孽
One more thing for me to atone for.
哦陛下 您……我可以坐下吗？
Your Grace, do you... may I?
您介意吗？
Do you mind?
我的膝盖不太中用了
It's my knees.
你坐吧
Of course.
您的母亲踏上赎罪之行
When your mother made her walk of atonement,
是为了回到您身边
she did it to get back to you.
我还是不明白你为什么不依不饶
I still don't understand why you want to put her
还要让她承受更多折磨
through any more than she's already endured.
并不是我要这样做 是诸神
It's not what I want. It's what the gods want.
诸神向我们传达旨意
They make their will known to us and it's up to us
是否遵从则取决于我们
to either accept or reject it.
请坐
Please.
如果我们一心向善 追求公正
If we're to be just and good,
那所有人都得遵从诸神的旨意 包括国王在内
then we accept it, all of us, even kings.
真正的领袖会让最睿智者来辅佐他
A true leader avails himself of the wisest counsel he can.
而没有谁比诸神更睿智
And no one is wiser than the gods.
我祖父和我说过类似的话
My grandfather once said something similar.
但他并没提到诸神的部分
Except for the part about the gods.
诸神透过他的嘴教诲你 无论他自己有没有意识到
The gods worked through him whether he knew it or not.
正如诸神也透过您的母亲
As they work through your mother.
每个人的内心都充满善意
There's so much good in all of us.
而我们能做的是引导他人向善
The best we can do is to help each other bring it out.
无名之辈
艾莉亚
你是谁？
Who are you?
无名之辈
No one.
你在来这里之前是谁？
Who were you before you came here?
艾莉亚·史塔克
Arya Stark.
跟我讲讲艾莉亚·史塔克的家庭
Tell me about Arya Stark's family.
她的父亲是艾德·史塔克
Her father was Eddard Stark.
她的母亲是凯特琳·史塔克
Her mother was Catelyn Stark.
她有一个姐姐 珊莎
She had one sister, Sansa,
还有四个兄弟
and four brothers.
三个兄弟
Three brothers.
罗柏 布兰 瑞肯
Robb, Bran, Rickon.
以及同父异母的哥哥琼恩
And a half-brother Jon.
他们现在何处？
And where are they now?
就女孩所知 他们可能已经死了
They may be dead for all a girl knows.
跟我讲讲猎狗的事
Tell me about the Hound.
他也死了
Also dead.
艾莉亚·史塔克丢下他等死 他在她的名单上
Arya Stark left him to die. He was on her list.
他不在她的名单上
He was not on her list anymore.
她把他从里面去掉了
She had taken him off it.
为什么？她不想让他死了吗？
Why? Didn't she want him dead any longer?
她既想又不想
She did and she did not.
她听起来很困惑
She sounds confused.
是的 她很困惑
Yes, she was.
还有谁在艾莉亚·史塔克可笑的小名单上？
Who else was on Arya Stark's funny little list?
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
Cersei Lannister.
格雷果·克里冈
Gregor Clegane.
瓦德·佛雷
Walder Frey.
这名单挺短的
That's a short list.
你想杀的人肯定不止这些
That can't be everyone you want to kill.
你确定自己没有忘记谁吗？
Are you sure you're not forgetting someone?
你想让女孩说出哪个名字？
Which name would you like a girl to speak?
如果女孩告诉某人她的名字
If a girl tells me her name,
某人会把眼睛还给她
I will give her eyes back.
女孩没有名字
A girl has no name.
贾昆·赫加尔
过来
Come.
如果女孩真的是无名之辈
If a girl is truly no one,
那她应当无所畏惧
she has nothing to fear.
你是谁？
Who are you?
无名之辈
No one.
安柏家族可是以忠诚著称
The Umbers are a famously loyal house.
以忠诚于史塔克著称
Famously loyal to the Starks.
拉姆斯·波顿
而你 卡史塔克大人
And you, Lord Karstark.
你的家族与史塔克有共同的血脉 不是吗？
Your people share blood with the Starks, don't they?
我们却都来到这里 世易时移
But here we are. Times change.
当我父亲成为北境守护的时候
When my father became Warden of the North,
你的家族拒绝向他效忠
your house refused to pledge their banners.
你父亲是个混蛋
Your father was a cunt.
我亲爱的父亲 北境守护……
My beloved father, the Warden...
你父亲是个混蛋 所以你杀了他
Your father was a cunt and that's why you killed him.
想来我大概也会这么对付我父亲
I might have done the same to my father
如果他没有行行好自己死掉的话
if he hadn't have done me the favor of dying on his own.
我父亲是被我们的敌人毒害的
My father was poisoned by our enemies.
你来临冬城做什么 安柏大人？
Why have you come to Winterfell, Lord Umber?
那个野种琼恩·雪诺率领一支野人军队过了长城
The bastard Jon Snow led an army of wildlings past the Wall.
我们的领地比你们这帮混球更靠北
We're farther north than any of you fuckers.
每当野人南下 我们总是首先拿起武器
Wildlings come down, we always have to fight them first.
我喜欢打野人 我一辈子都在干这事
I like fighting wildlings. Been doing it all my life.
但他们人太多了 我们没法单干
But there are too many of them for us to beat back alone.
所以你现在是来求助？
So now you've come seeking help?
我们得互相帮助
We need to help each other.
天气越冷 那些操山羊的蛮子就会越往南迁徙
The colder it gets, the farther south those goat fuckers will roam.
过不了多久就会到这儿
Won't take them long to get here.
你觉得一群野人能攻占临冬城？
You think a horde of wildlings can take Winterfell?
如果有琼恩·雪诺作他们的头儿 那可说不准
If they get Jon Snow leading them, maybe.
他远比我们中的任何人更了解这里
He knows this place better than we ever will.
向波顿家族宣誓效忠
Pledge your banners to House Bolton.
承认我为北境守护
Swear loyalty to me as Warden of the North
我就与你并肩作战 除掉那个野种
and we will fight together to destroy the bastard
外加他所有的野人朋友
and all his wildling friends.
我不会吻你的脏手
I'm not kissing your fucking hand.
按传统 封臣应向封君下跪
Traditionally a bannerman kneels before his lord.
我也不会这么做
I'm not doing that either.
琼恩·安柏
小琼恩
我凭什么要相信一个不尊重传统的人？
Why would I trust a man who won't honor tradition?
你父亲尊重传统
Your father honored tradition.
他向罗柏·史塔克下跪
Knelt for Robb Stark.
拥戴其为北境之王
Called him King of the North.
罗柏·史塔克应当相信你父亲吗？
Was Robb Stark right to trust your father?
看来 我们陷入了一个小小的僵局
Then it appears we're at a bit of an impasse.
去他妈的下跪 去他妈的宣誓
Fuck kneeling and fuck oaths.
我有个礼物给你
I've got a gift for you.
希望是个姑娘 我喜欢红发的
A girl, I hope. I prefer redheads.
姑娘 有的
A girl, aye.
一个女野人
A wild one.
欧莎
耶人
我喜欢带野性的
I like them wild.
还有个男孩 年轻又健康
And the boy, nice and young.
卡史塔克大人肯定喜欢
The way Karstark likes them.
这是谁？
Who's this?
瑞肯·史塔克
Rickon Stark.
你怎么证明这是瑞肯·史塔克？
How do I know that's Rickon Stark?
瑞肯·史塔克
欢迎回家 史塔克大人
Welcome home, Lord Stark.
时间到了
It's time.
有什么遗言 现在说吧
If you have any last words, now is the time.
你不该活着
You shouldn't be alive.
这不该发生
It's not right.
你们也不该谋杀我
Neither was killing me.
波文·马尔锡
总务长
奥赛尔·亚威克
首席工匠
我母亲还住在白港
My mother's still living at White Harbor.
你能写信给她吗？
Could you write her?
告诉她我死在与野人的战斗中
Tell her I died fighting the wildlings.
我有过选择 总司令大人
I had a choice, Lord Commander.
艾里沙·索恩
守夜人教头
背叛你或背叛守夜人
Betray you or betray the Night's Watch.
你将一支野人军队带到了我们的土地上
You brought an army of wildlings into our lands.
一支杀人犯和掠袭者组成的军队
An army of murderers and raiders.
如果让我知道结局 再重来一次
If I had to do it all over knowing where I'd end up,
我祈祷自己能再次做出正确的选择
I pray I'd make the right choice again.
我确信你会的 艾里沙爵士
I'm sure you would, Ser Alliser.
我战斗过 我失败了
I fought, I lost.
我可以安心休息
Now I rest.
可是你 雪诺大人
But you, Lord Snow,
你将永世不得翻身
you'll be fighting their battles forever.
奥利
我们应该烧掉这些尸体
We should burn the bodies.
不 是你应该
You should.
你干嘛把这个给我？
What do you want me to do with this?
穿上它
Wear it.
或者烧了它
Burn it.
想怎样都行
Whatever you want.
黑城堡是你的了
You have Castle Black.
我的守望于斯结束
My watch is ended.
衣柜字幕组出品
本集关键字：极乐塔之战 欧莎 多希卡林
剧情没看懂？ 典故不清楚？
维基新站网址：http://asoiaf.huiji.wiki/